[Music]
Alexander barred the wall of thought
this was a reference to my discussion
with John for Vicki who described
Alexander as a wall of sound referring
to Phil Spector's famous well assumed
yeah
but I stopped being a record producer so
I I and I did like more is more so I
actually I was flattered with it Phil
Spector of comparison but obviously as a
philosopher you prefer to be the wall of
thought rather than the world son right
yeah no kidding even there's a wall of
information to be honest about it
yeah I think a wall of beautiful ideas
would be even better hopefully also
coherent ideas I think what striking
with us will meet somebody who's like
overwhelming us is there is that the
first thing we need to find out is what
whether what they say stick together or
not is there a coherent worldview here
and that's when it gets really
impressive and and you and I've been
hanging out now with some truly systemic
thinkers lately we got for them in
America one of them overseas Joan for
parking and another one is Greg
Henriques who's built the tree of
knowledge system and he's challenging
the orthodoxy in the world on psychology
because of it he's also a friend of
John's obviously and we got and we got
the two guys downing in San Diego we got
Jordan halls and Daniel's Magdeburg
girls work together and see each other
almost every day and what is striking
with these guys and you get it because
you're in on it is that they all seem to
have these sort of highly systemic
brains and they come they all come out
of complexity science one way or the
other
Greg bobasa's arrived in the world of
psychology John Ferber key in the world
of cognitive science I'm obviously the
world of philosophy Jordan and Daniel
probably don't even want to be
associated with in a specific field yet
they're that well but when he started
with all these Minds is that the very
systemic and why we love each other is
because we we have found out that
actually these systemic worldviews that
be presented to us all coherent and
obviously then the whole dance to get
started is one of compare
ten studies it's just like okay where
did you arrive at this have I understood
you correctly did I misunderstand you
and is there more to it yeah at least
that we can put together to put together
what I think is going to be eventually
very very impressive possible to be
honest about it very impressive jigsaw
if that hopefully people can then use
obviously no no I said I said beauty but
uh you know um I was talking to John and
he was talking about his part his his
writing partner um Chris Christopher
master uh Pietro who's kind of a poet
and he was talking about the combination
of those two guys when they worked
together they end up creating something
more sublime than they could create on
their own so so yeah John John's the guy
who who builds the ideas and and
Kristof's he said he furnishes them with
with this sort of great great that's
good I mean this you want like that a
bit with John what I look philosopher so
I am already in a world of art I'm an
artist and a competent scientist is not
and that explains why I love working
with scientists and and my greatest
inspiration for this new really
important hard to write and hard to
think book the young so - Chris no have
challenges other right this is no
mythology of the future so to speak okay
to write that book I am surrounded by
engineers I work with you know
engineering geniuses I work with these
people who are have systemic minds - but
they're completely obsessed with
construction and engineering and and I
want to get into their minds and
understand why the work the way you do
because obviously I'm a phallus
worshipper I believe that's what's
needed in society today I am a
Zoroastrian even you can't get more
phallic than that and I think when we
talk about the comparative study between
say John for variks work and what I'm up
to
or mighty me substitute honest about I
think what is striking there it reminds
me of where Erich von Stein is a if you
think of Erich von Stein as a character
that sits between Jordan Pederson and
Peter the--
and I'm Peter Thiel and Gautam Petersen
is the join for market so Eric Weinstein
is he's all that is best when he's
actually being held responsible by EDP
you feel or Jordan Peterson that's what
he shines cuz he can complement them
perfectly in his role but you play that
role between me and John by the way
right now right so so you don't have to
take a stand or anything like that at
all you can just bring out the best out
of the Jordan Peter so bring out the
best I'm Peter Thiel but what is
important here is that the bigger
picture that comes out is quite dramatic
now there are some really drastic
differences here there are very very
well you've said you're a fellow fellows
worshipper and
when I was having that discussion with
John I kind of brought up your
vocabulary and I could feel almost an
instinctive like no it's like this kind
of languages is is is tough for people
because it's sexual and I think
sexuality is or is thank you that's the
point okay we have probably to begin
with we have to understand but even if
John spit all over the place and he's
incredibly learned I mean this guy knows
so much and that's one of the beauties
of his mind but when he speaks of his
religion which is kind of a chicken race
why don't you just say religion if you
mean religion why do you talk about
religion that's not a religion when you
really talk about original that's more
religion than whatever legend we had in
the past that's what I think at least
he's talking about certainly I do and
what religion is here is the essence
what is religion right because because
because hold on there because John John
wants to separate religio from really
Gary which would be the dogmatic aspect
of religion right he wants to separate
those two things he's a chicken that's
that's just that's just escaping from
the hard work that's not the way it
works to say you're not dogmatic is in
itself dogmatic learn Hegel you cannot
be brilliant as a thinker on this you
understand Hegel he's falling straight
into a ghost trap people who say you
must not be dogmatic because I'm scared
of dogma have just declared a dogmatic
approach
claritin on approach no no it's that
there is no such thing as an on approach
okay that is an approach in itself you
have you have set the rules for the game
by saying that and you then also become
the judge who can say that anybody's too
dogmatic in this room somebody I'm
uncomfortable with and they should leave
that's why I'm saying it's a chicken
race he's running John is brilliant in
so many ways but let's go straight to
the point here what is religion well to
me and I come through the world of
psychoanalysis and I come from deep
history and deep philosophy okay for me
it's obvious that their religion is
something that interrupts our lives
dramatically we live in fantasies our
lives our families this shot la comic
French psychosis we live in fantasies
and these different fantasies to
struggle one another and and we think
we're alive and we think we're coming to
grips to the world because they're
different fantasies to struggle one
another
then suddenly the real not reality the
real it can be anything just strikes
like a bombs from your life somebody we
love dies in front of us what can we
collect your things say September 11
okay yeah it caught everybody everybody
it was caught with surprise massive
surprise shocked all those institutions
we thought were stable that would
protect us suddenly fell apart there was
nothing there and we realized actually
the void we're living on top of so to
understand religion is to understand
that the real breaks into our fantasy
this is how you describe it with the
vocabulary from psychoanalysis I would
prefer another of a cabinet that develop
a Peter Towson wine or work with lovely
Peter my research director here and
Peters come up with this idea that we
should still use of vocabulary we talk
about horizontal and the vertical oh
yeah John Jackson - yeah yeah
so John knows what I'm talking about a
single cuz he knows the history religion
the axis mundi is vertical right but we
live in a very horizontal world the
horizontal world is something you and
I've talked about a lot course also
called a matriarchy yeah or a magical
world okay you come out of the womb
you're scared like shit you want to die
the first thing you do so the death
Drive is there initially you cannot kill
yourself
so that's turned into the conviction
that you want to live and then you get
the tit in your mouth and as soon as you
get to kick in your mouth you believe
you're reunited with the womb you don't
exist any longer
you're dissolved right so we stay in
that environment the first year of our
lives until the phallus comes along and
the phallus could literally even be your
father's penis walking by you or
something like that but phallus is what
the male grown-up body represents to us
when we suddenly discover there's
something there that takes away mothers
attention and again smothers something
that I cannot give her so I become
something the plunders the mother's body
but this magical thing this phallus
gives mother the energy and the strength
to give me the breast milk and this gets
degrading and in a certain moment the
mothers take those well that was
wonderful object in the world that will
forever miss after that moment until the
most hated thing whatever encounter in
our lives we objectify them others take
we have to push it away with anger to go
towards the phallus insight about about
I guess the struggle between men and
women or something a psyche but that's
that's minor here let's forget about the
father and the mother this is about you
this is about you being a baby being
one-year-old and for the first time
separating yourself from the tip seeing
the fathers are something you aspire to
Freud literally says this is when the
girl wants to have the father's penis
inside of her this is when the boy wants
to have the father's penis okay forget
less than people the opposite doesn't
matter so you want to be phallic you
want to get to the phallic you want to
have in you you want to be it you would
start for it this is the grown-up world
and this is the first experience of
transcendence the first experience of
transcendence is that the child wants to
become a child to then become an adult
and if this doesn't work this phallic
intrusion doesn't work you're fucked
that one's fun that you're fun the
proudly contempt for society according
to our book digital libido is that this
is exactly what we put out a function it
is the totally dysfunctional the phallic
transitions are not happening on the
scale in the population that they need
happen for us to have a civilized
society we have become radical
infantilized so we postpone our
transcendence as these are the things
that John talks about like you should
self transcendence what at least why
does he talk literally about the actual
transcendence system must happen because
what's dramatic about this is that if
the phallic intuition doesn't happen to
work wonder awake you will not have your
teenager value when you're 13 when you
biologically push away your parents and
shit test them to then come back to and
find if you're actually quite similar to
your parents but you're still in Rome
and that's when you're ready for the
rite of passage and going to adulthood
and this whole process is something I
call this part I do know Peterson I call
this adult if occasion that's lacking in
our society but it's lacking because the
phallic transition the Phatak intrusion
itself is not happening at one year of
age we're postponing everything in our
lives
we're postponing everything we're
postponing adulthood so we're pushing
everything forward this is the real
death of God because ultimately and this
is what John has been very helpful with
me in our own conversations it's obvious
that the child has to become an adult
yeah
then it also means God is nothing but
the names what the adult aspires to be
later in life but actually this is step
in between that I had a far too Western
view when I saw this first because it's
not at all that the adult looks to
become a god no that's when it gets
really bad
no the adult looks to the priesthood to
the sage as dopher Warka says correctly
we look to the sage there aspire to be
like the sage so that the adult has
somebody he can mimic the way the child
mimics the adult yeah so this
development process has been completely
broken let's say Ethan the grief is not
in meaning crisis this is a crisis of
transcendence --is this is a crisis of
the rites of passages that have to work
in a culture and if they don't work
if these grace the fact that there isn't
that that transition that the meaning
crisis might be another the result of
that it's the result of that it's the
result of that we'd love and care would
like to dress what John is talking about
and where I see where I could teat not a
criticism a critique like friendly
approach to strengthen the arguments on
the other side but John and I wanted a
stronger one be better so we want to
help each other here okay so phallus
it's not something I pick out there like
something I worship I am just
identifying with one-year-olds of the
world mm-hmm that is what we all have to
be phallus worshipers because to be a
phallus worship it is as a child is to
aspire to become a grown-up and once
you're a grown-up to take responsibility
for yourself your community and to
aspire to one day become a parent and
why do you become a parent you aspire to
one day hopefully become an elder if you
live that long yeah and then we are an
elder this is what's interesting and
this is where it gets really really
tough because now we have to go further
back than just the last four hundred
years and being Fanta lies a tional
society that so deep this type we write
about it in Tianjin libido the sorry for
showing the books around it this time
around I think it's necessary so in
digital libido and this is the
interesting thing
go back to John John for Warka Gregg
Henricus Daniel smack the burger in
Jordan Hall are all synthesis mm-hmm
they're fantastic synthesis so if you
take the first book we wrote in the
grand narrative you get a synth isn't
book yeah they get this they live this
they even do it better the improve on it
they work on it but that's the container
they get stuck in because obviously when
we wrote the synth is invoke and it's
the first part of a trilogy it was to
first create a container within which we
then put the critique what's the problem
with the container why will it not work
unless it's modified to then point
towards what can and must be done that's
why it's a trilogy so my frustration
with John is partly by referring to my
own work with John said it is he said he
gets stuck of the synthesis and book and
he's like afraid of taking the step on
to do this liberty
and this is a guy who knows Freud this
is a guy who knows Jung yeah this is a
guy who knows all the brilliant
anthropologist of the 20th century
Marseille liard and you know all these
guys the lead up to your Peters and
compiler today and when you take their
critique of our society the society we
live in they agree strongly with me in
your city kissed well here's an immense
infantilized mass infantilization is the
current problem revenge it hasn't
mentioned renergie road
neither as jordan Peterson and and
jordan do you think something jordan
Peterson and John burger Vicki talk
about sacrifice I think John maybe he
stops at the Greeks he finds the Greeks
but even John now admits he does problem
axiom age that every teacher including
John up until now was declared it's the
most fantastic thing that happened
because you know about eight hundred
before Christ
simultaneously China India the Middle
Eastern Europe the civilized world okay
there is an axial revolution right but I
disagree strongly but the axial H was a
great image I think many of the problems
of dealing with they actually come from
out of that age and that's exactly says
who were to world mythology
he's criticizes that ages to no big deal
so listen he has two big history voids
in his understanding of the history of
ideas he hasn't started per shot yes and
studied Egypt properly because if he had
done that he knows that the axial age is
actually dealing with a successful and a
failed revolution that happened about
five and years before the axial age
it starts with Zoroaster in Iran in
Central Asia who declares the first
monotheistic religion a does so
successfully three major Persian empires
are eventually built on that religion
and I would still say it's a very
grown-up religion it's essentially a
religion absolutely about adulthood and
transcendence and putting yourself in
your place in society and don't think
you can be anything outside where you're
set that's exactly so a schism works I
converted to it myself
I see strong resurrection
and a restoration is Western ISM is
needed to complement the picture at
least to the west before we can look at
least in the West and compare them but
we also have to remember this is about
mimicking again ready sure are exactly
renewed you've read rené girard Peter
Thiel was his favorite student like up
Sean P on Cooper you from I think the
scapegoat is the key here because all of
this all of the fear that John has about
totalitarianism and and all that that's
the scapegoat I mean you call it the
algae no no no no we talked about it
before let's go back to what I mentioned
about the sonic intrusion okay your
mother's tip turns from the most loved
object in the world into the most hated
that is objectification scapegoating is
merely the jet education in a larger
population
you won't even find irony sure I'll
really find about work so to understand
scapegoating you first have to
understand why you hate your mother's
tit so to to have a unified world you
you gotta have something you terrified
on you got out of something incredibly
track it to you got something you'd be
spy some push away and you've got
something you pulled in by so you gotta
have these objects around you relate to
that gives you values is that the
vertical maybe the heaven in hell you
have to have something high brilliant or
two and then tell your great again
no you're brilliant you're ahead of the
game okay but let's go back to what I
talked about prior to the axial age
about 300 years after so Rasta Mustafa
successfully declared the first person
Empire where the state religion called
Zoroastrianism and does so successfully
the Egyptians are inspired by the
persian experiment okay
they then suddenly 1300 before Christ a
lady called up not on SERPs word and at
not an declares a whole new religion an
Egyptian version or modify so called
atomism
there's a problem though and that is
that so Rastus religion was created in a
landscape of two rivers you've got the
hills up there you've got
see you down there with two rivers
floating next to each other and has to
be relation between the rivers this is
where the Cain and Abel mythology comes
from how do you create peaceful
sustainable relationship between the two
rivers that area is called transics Anya
and that's in Central Asia that then
arrived in babylon babylon are you
threatened tigress is he the same thing
repeat itself so you can have a
successful function more efficient that
was born in Persia came to Babylon still
work the problems were that arrived in
Egypt what does the Egyptian landscape
look like one River why do you think the
Egyptians were the ones who invented
totalitarianism mm-hmm perspective not
another no it is all about the phallus
their phallus is completely unified and
only one fellas the thing with Sora
asters unique understanding of the human
condition was to understand the phallus
is split the phallus expect between the
chief Kang and the priest okay between
the body and the mind or as I say
confrontationally to mana do men's work
between the dick between your legs and
the dick you hopefully have in your head
so to understand masculinity they
understand where men strive to go
because they always want to get out
there in the world you have to
understand the phallus Ozma split that
means really great leadership it's like
Moses and Aaron or so a certain visto
spot is arrested and we got Moses and
Aaron Judaism is between the chieftain
in the priests who work and collaborate
and respect and love each other to bits
and admire each other for each other's
strengths hmm so all successful
patriarchy's this is what Jon for Barca
does he's just scared of Patrick you
period and scare the fellas period no
what without fellas we die we die so we
have to have fallows the problem with
contemporary society could separate
meaning crisis the young fervor arc is
missing is that the reason for the mini
crisis that killed the phallus
completely after 1945 and we're stuck
with a mess ever since it's called
post-modernism and it's a fucking poison
and even only lead to the resurrection
even worse totalitarianism
maybe it's from world war one even with
all the death of those fathers
no no no wait a second wait a second
okay good point thinking of the fellas
in terms of yeah let's not go too much
into the footnotes because you're
brilliant we get back to the talking so
let's go back to the topic here so we
can go back and explain that we can do
that later we did it in the deliberate
or if you if you really wonder stand the
difference doing an authentic and a fake
follows between an authentic Messiah and
it's fake Messiah and the world is full
of fake Messiah substantive precise are
rare but needed okay there you can read
digital libido so you understand it but
the thing here is that when you
understand the phallus is split so the
why the match arc is not split the
metric is basically the oldest wisest
woman in the tribe what she's only going
to push the whole tribe forward she's
fucking Margaret Thatcher that's what
metrics are but if you're gonna lead and
seduce and pull an entire population
you better have somebody you can look up
to physiologically that's the chief Kang
he's the warrior he goes into the
fighting and all that you gotta have a
priest who gets the picture who has to
picture clear - he uses his mind
brilliantly to then support the chief
came in the army so they can do their
job right so you gotta have Moses and
Aaron at the front that you got Miriam
the sister at the Battle Creek that is
the perfect picture of know about olives
yeah so if you have the priests the
priesthood that runs amok then you have
a crazy society and if you have the just
a warrior who runs amuck then you have a
crazy society if they ever get these are
the to have to be Italy ever get a
leader who says he's both the chief gent
and the priest you get the tyrant this
is exactly what happens in Egypt 1300
before Christ and Freud realized this
the OL adult Freud is so fucking
brilliant he's like a super Vivar cos
superb are even on Hegel's lovely you
know but Freud realized this was an old
man that he needed to go back to his own
Jewish roots and understand Judaism to
really truly understand why the West and
there I include the Middle East the
Middle East no part fucked so he went
back to Judaism and its roots and he
found out
obviously the juice came out of Egypt
originally and they were obviously
almost left of atomism after actions it
was destroyed because what happened was
that as soon as if Norton was gone in a
very powerful dictator okay they were
only allowed to worship him and he was
only one of the only ones allowed to
worship the Sun now is it minimalist
religion right so his son Tutankhamun
took over Nia was of course you know the
result of incest for several generations
probably quite dysfunctional so the
Egyptian priests conspired and said this
tyranny is daughter collegiate we got to
get rid of the Pharaoh we gotta kill our
own God so they killed Tutankhamun Jesus
Christ on the cross is obviously only
mimicking of the whole thing right so
they killed the Tutankhamun this is
where the scapegoating comes in or Freud
and Shearer are fit into the picture so
they kill total come and get rid of him
and then the Aten is there are left in
Egypt become a small minority they
probably put on their slavery and
pressure of the brilliant in many ways
and they think you know brilliantly and
eventually they leave and what saves
them from repeating the mistakes of
ignore is when they arrived in qur'an
they pick up el from the continent
religion and to keep yahweh themselves
so they keep the sun god from one
religion and they take a rain god from
the other this is exactly what the solar
Astra's did in persia and what worked
the sun god and the rain garden all
polyphasic religions are always
separated they must not be the same die
the Sun God is the maintainer father in
Christianity the rain God is yo the
perpetrator he's the warrior but he's
also the guy who fucks you know the
earth and puts it to get him makes it
prosper and then grow and and the rain
gotta solve it you got to keep the if
you got to keep these two gods separate
and every polytheistic religion and
Hinduism is perfect example that every
policy stiffly didn't keep separate when
you move into monoface and say get rid
of all the other gods let's have only
one God you must not have fantasy of a
pharmacist unified because that kills
the phallus mmm the tyrant is a dead
phallus he's not alive right he's not
listening to anybody he's just he's
building pyramids
no that's what the dip just did the
purchase never did that the purchase
were wealthier more successful their
empires lasted longer even the Egyptians
you don't see a single pyramid anywhere
in Seoul Raskin irani culture Egypt's
fill the pyramids and I tell you one
thing because they're not trying a means
you're not they're not trying to reify
civilization they're allowing it to be
dynamic and a parameter Asian death it's
yes as a construction it is absolutely
useless except for one thing and that is
to put stupid dead boy pharaoh's corpse
inside of it hmm it the point was the
transcendence in the Zoroastrian
tradition you go to the Chenevert and
then the priests the mobile tell you you
cannot cross this universe you cannot
get me like that the Buddhist promised
you for example you cannot get that way
your life only the priests can walk
across the shin of a bridge and back and
forth as much as he likes only the
priests can be in the most sacred room
mm-hmm
the most sacred room is barred tea we
call the closed stops with the court it
is the part of not be ard my name is ba
RR e D because that's a
psychoanalytically correct description
the bard absolutely God must not be
accessible to you so what the surahs
just knew was that you cannot have a
direct accessibility between God and man
because if you have it then you also
have a direct accessibility between God
and man the other direction because God
would just destroy you sort of thing he
will certainly cause constant travel as
he wishes you weren't ready you're not
ready for him your this is that problem
yeah we're stuck with the West with a
Cain and Abel situation with two
inferior religions it became popular and
widespread because they promised us that
all anything
stood between man and God had been
removed Kristiana claims that happened
when Christ died on the cross when they
say that the curtain in the temple fell
and suddenly not only the sacred room
was available but the most sacred room
you could look straight into the heart
of God
anybody could look st. Aragon can you
now understand why the Jews never could
accept Christianity because the Jews had
learned the hard way in Babylon from the
Celestials and for God's sake don't
repeat it not this mistake in Egypt you
live in a in it in a landscape of the
two rivers Cain and Abel all that heat
el and Yahweh so the wife is enjoyed
Jewish rabbi say that he thought that
you know Paul may even even Jesus was
saying oh no no don't let the Gentiles
in or something like this right but
actually was Paul that said you know
open it up for everybody or that is
where we have to go next well the
apparent digital limiters that we said
that modernity turn us all to infants
and after 1945 we've gone completely
bonkers in our heads because we never
worship youth before in any culture ever
in human history and now were we all
worship youth and we're gonna die from
because the lack of wisdom so you know
this is where John Farrar can I agree
this Ilana was but the the idea that I
could be instant infant wisdom at all
it's the problem with Christianity
Christianity doesn't worship the fellows
Christianity worships the mother and the
child as if the child knew everything as
if the child was a priest ready to see
God their worship innocence or something
like that this would be absurd to the
persons in the babylonians absurd and
they would certainly see the same
mistake that happened he dipped
happening all over again but we have it
as an extended mistake over 2,000 years
the problem was that than 600 years
later because that door had been open
already somebody came along and said oh
by the way I'm going to create another
Braunger pop religion
everybody would like and I'm gonna
really do with God has instant access to
men all the time
welcome to slaw okay the problem we got
is that while Christianity in Islam are
fighting the war between each other the
rest of us just step back for a while
and say maybe both of these two
religions are fundamentally wrong and
maybe we need to go back to what
psychoanalysis says or dude essence says
what so asterism told us all along and
that is there must not be any any idea
whatsoever that there's a direct link
between man and God that's exactly why
there is a priesthood in between to
prevent man from ever seeing God and the
priesthood are the ones who do not catch
ildren out there in the world who do not
fight over heritage - not part of the
intrigues they retract from society they
step outside society to not be part of
the power game that goes on in the
square so they stay out in the
monasteries they live their own isolated
lives as a shamanic cast precisely so
that they can have direct access to God
so we can go to them when we need to
communicate with the divine but the
divine only comes back and crushes
straight into our lives yeah you made me
think of art enter violence and that's
religion to you yeah that's really if if
if John for Warka doesn't get I think he
does there hold on a minute hold on a
minute I lost you when you said that's
religion just just go back religion is
religion okay okay
anything that suddenly can break into
your life and you cannot complete it and
it shakes up completely and it tells you
how powerless you are and it makes a bit
respectful of fate goddess so you have
to sort of read you know you recalibrate
your worldview so so the way shockula
conscious is that we live in a series of
fantasies and what the real dose is that
shakes us up and reminds us that these
are just fantasies there are religions
shoot them we create new fantasies out
of whatever material we got available to
us that we hope think that we hope are
better
and this is what we perceive as
transcendence the development so that's
how it works
and that's exactly the way I see John is
he practices synth ISM and I agree with
Greg on because this should be called
American citizen by the way centrosome
is a theological term for anybody to use
synthesis yeah explain explain a little
bit more in nuanced detail what Cynthia
Thurman okay Cynthia so Mr Hague alien
understanding that the that the conflict
between fearsome atheism a bit like the
conflict between Christianity and Islam
it's a fake conflict they have the same
problem that you both got way the same
we face him in atheism fearful
interesting is he's actually actually
what we talked about me and Verve a key
is what he conclusion he came to is is
that the false dichotomy between between
theism and non-theism
you know because Buddhism is usually
considered non theism and he said that
yeah actually no that's not the point
yet the pointer is what why do we use
the word God to begin with we use the
word God because it's the name we put on
the board absolute so when when you look
at yourself you discover that your chaos
and that's exactly why our to invent a
fantasy that you're somehow organized
and ordered and that illusion is called
the self it's the same thing when you
then relate to the outside world around
you you think of the world you discover
that the world is chaos you cannot live
with chaos so you gotta find one point
in that case any point
it's called objectivity up when you
study shuttle con azúcar you gotta found
one point that you stare at and because
you can stare at at one point suddenly
the world seems organized to that very
point is what we're going to call the
barred absolute in the new book because
the subjectivity that shall be she talks
about from Lacan he calls the barred
subject okay fair enough
why don't we just call God than the
barred absolute so God is just a name
for whatever order we perceive in the
chaos of the world that isn't us
that's the name God okay so you say you
don't believe in God you certainly
believe there's some kind of order to
the world or wherever you put your eyes
and place that order
that's your God that's all this to it so
they another question anything personal
like you know no that's just an American
consumerism he was talking about I'm
referring back to my conversation with
were Vegas okay talking about theists
usually want to personalize God and he
was saying non-theistic goes one step
that's just I know narcissists and I'm
not interested I find it boring can we
please stop talking about American
individual style for just for once the
problem here also be John for vitamin
he's going to start marketing his
American synthesis is that he will only
he will only be able to market it as
another critical consumer product as
another item out in the spirituality
market unless he starts to rethink the
phallus okay so just step back a bit
here look at the bigger picture it needs
to be explained
okay yeah so the bard absolute to God
this is the name for that synthesis of
essential it's just a position that wait
a second if God is something that we
tried to find in the world and it gives
us order to the world then if we don't
believe this God exists because we
believe there's only chaos then maybe we
can create God well turns out that's
what we did all along we create that
internalization that little objective
fixed object in the chaos of the world
to have some focal point to look at
that's exactly why we got the phallic
gaze I'll go that the creative principle
or something like that that's why we
obsessed with Google Maps at the moment
because we suddenly discover being
watched by gods these gods are called
satellites and we love them to bits and
we perform for them that's called the
Internet that's a theater so synthesis
basically just says okay we need a
religion
don't Iraq Isis religion that's sort of
like I said that's bullshit he should
rather say that it's finally a proper
religion he should dare to declare the
Christianity in Islam they
you know they were popular but they
weren't right and usually when things
get popular he's usually not right they
just flattering it was flattering to
hear that you could be born as a little
innocent baby and you could have all the
Western of the world from day one and
now you look at what happened in Europe
in 1945 the bomb went off and if
anything has has you know pull in our
collective subconsciousness really made
a mark on us it is the atomic bomb in
1945 and then of course the satellites
came in 1958 and we got some hope again
but we're in between these two images of
the satellites looking over us that's
why machine intelligence gets attractive
I love darkness Mac the burgers and
doughnut holes work on symbiotic
intelligence I think the relationship
between machine and man should
definitely be seen as not as competitive
the rather complimentary and very very
needed we're not going to solve the
current crisis without the machines but
the satellites and ultimately she's to
look at us they got the phallic gaze
when we think of the barred absolutely
we think that there's a god out there's
that we find somewhere in the chaos to
need some order to the chaos we also
think of that as an eye that's why
there's always an eye know everywhere
the Sun did solo either look God's eye
that looks at us this we call the
phallic gaze you know work so we're
looking for the Fela case to look at us
the problem is this after the bomb went
off in 1945 we immediately started
analyzing the Second World War and
decided that Hitler will start to
medieval and by the way we had a second
Alta medieval - and he was Stalin okay
what John fervently doesn't seem to
realize it is precisely when you're
scared of the phallus a when avoided and
you start creating little playtest
Gnostic cults and call them religio
that's exactly you open the space for
another Hitler or another Stalin because
if you start saying that the must of you
fellows there must have been a Dogma
which associated with fathers an order
there must only be chaos that we embrace
I think I missed that's when you open or
did you adopt and something we said that
exactly that there was the dogma
an important I think he had a he was a
bit had a bit more sophisticated a view
than sure but any but anyway that's um I
don't want I love him to bits her person
no no no thank you for doing that saying
that but the problem is that after 1945
we declared that Hitler was ultimate
evil the problem with that is that
anything that is against Hitler is then
considered brilliant so what happened
was we created a culture of mass
mediocrity ok well maybe just Timothy
were if we're safe now because Hitler
and no no no no safety no you don't even
understand you don't even stand how big
this crisis is what actually happened
with America starting with America which
by the way is some mimicking culture the
mimics Europe in many ways but in coming
from America in the 1950s comes the idea
of the teenager waiting we talked about
that yeah yeah the God said goddess is
suddenly called James Dean and Marilyn
Monroe even go to kill themselves to
keep their beaut beauty in youth ok
youth worshipped Beauty worship is
always historically really busy
oh I can add one more thing you
sacrifice almost it's like you know with
all the what if you guys should use a
beauty and innocence that means you hate
wisdom yeah
because wisdom is only earned through
hard work deep studies and a long life
mmm-hmm there is no shorter to wisdom
any priest
any decent priest them always tell you
no you have to work hard study deep and
you have to live a long life to be
considered wise that's why you have to
be 8 years old or something before you
become an elder right you cannot you are
not born but since Christianity and the
same this is same problem with Islam we
got a problem with the idea that there's
instant wisdom available to us if you
only beg for it mm-hmm no wonder
capitalism arrives in Europe and thrives
and all that because capitalism also
promised I say if you want to get the
money it's begging for it you get
anything you like it's making prayer
begging for something's that
now understand the depth of the crisis
because it's consumer society the
brought us here the mass exploitation of
the planet hey you know climate crisis
but we got the bomb and now apparently
Donald Trump is fucking up with Iran and
probably Iran Turkey and Saudi Arabia
building bombs within the next five
years we're gonna widespread nuclear
weapons widespread biological weapons
widespread chemical weapons across the
planet put them drones with terrorist
sites everywhere this is why I did it a
liberal is a very dark book this is not
in control and it's not going to be in
control when I Eve little plate them his
boys tell us we cannot have done one and
you cannot have fallows we need the
Messiah
we need the phallus more than ever and
this time around we must learn the
lesson from previous mistakes well I
think definitely when you say we need
the Messiah that sounds true to me that
is the rostrum in Zoroastrianism is
called the social and what I prefer to
ask them and there's some over Judaism
is that the juice to borrow the idea of
the social and calling them a friar but
they want to make him a local phenomenon
the Messiah is there to save the Jewish
people because they are a religious
minority kinda have a question about
that for you actually that's arrest just
believe the social as a universal Savior
the steps in at the end of the
thousand-year Empire to save us from the
misery that we've created to save
everybody not just the ones who have
converted but to save at least those who
want to be saved
that is the you know the exodus is
offered the exodus is not forced on you
so communism is the name of that plan
yeah that's what my question was
communism okay how can you be such an
elitist in a communist at the same time
because Marx was too okay Rousseau and
Mart's are not the same guys Marx hated
Roseau Marx said that a small
proletariat would take over the world
and beat the capitalist at their own
game by creating a society where
creativity rather than capital was at
the forefront and they about creating a
society people would gladly join
that's why Stalinism is
but the workers compacta marks as SS
hitler's to nature right the workers are
not a small elite there he was talking
about the workers all the time was no no
he was talking about the people who
qualified according to the test of
beating the capitalists at their own
game
mm-hmm he said capitalism is the best
thing we but it was a it was a
bottoms-up movement rather than a but I
don't think we're gonna get stuck with
Marquez tonight okay but let's just put
it this way I read Marx through
Nietzsche and that's the way you must
read him
I hate Russell that Saudi Marx and Marx
didn't have a single good word for the
people of the streets of London a London
proletariat Marx would have hated
today's identity politicians he would
have hated the social justice worse you
were to consider them weak and spoiled
brats and you know they're not producing
anything they're not producing any value
and I'm proud of themselves they're
coming and begging and demanding more
tips that is the exact opposite of what
Karl Marx wrote about but socialism
because he became a big tit failed
socialism became a big tip well that's
that's so it failed mm-hmm even
according to Marx it wasn't only the
landing was too much in a hurry Marx
himself was too much in hurry yeah but I
think the potential for a communist
elite they do whatever they want and who
will take over a real the world as they
say fit whatever they want to rule
because I don't think they will want
most of us or most of the planets but I
think that's exactly what we're seeing
being established today and communism to
me is something that's realized not
through socialism at all the communism
is realized through the current state of
things which is called attentional ISM
we've left capitalism already we live
now an intention its world that's we
were obsessed with phallic cases as
we're obsessed with the satellites were
obsessed to the social theatre were
obsessed exhibitionism employer ISM
everything has become a spectacle it's
become a theater and this has become the
production itself
hmm so we left capitalism and we're now
in a state of attention as our marketing
is dead algorithms
their sonic algorithms are beautiful
love they're so funny algorithms are
killing the bullshit they're killing the
nonsense and the only thing you can do
in this society is to be really really
good at what you do
meaning there is a demand for Western
which is the armchair theory with
worship of had very very good news if
that was true I mean that would just be
there would be good news well I don't
think don't for Marc and these guys have
thought of this yet maybe Jordan Daniel
have I'm interested in going into that
dialogue because if we moved into the
state to potential is I mean I'm proving
it with the data with my team here that
2012 we did the shift since then you
don't look at the ads any longer you do
Google search you look at the algorithm
we just had the first university
professor in Sweden this week who
resigned from his post and said he never
ever will go back to any university at
all because he himself has only watched
YouTube for the past six years and all
the students do the same thing and he
knows the universities dead and over hmm
that's attentional ISM again so we
already moving quickly into new paradigm
and this is what ties in to John for
variks work what I've done with John
static list or the past five books is to
present a paradigm theory he works with
emergence theory so we both work with
how out of self-organization can magical
things suddenly occur hmm but what I'm
saying in my work is that paradigm
theory and emerges there it cannot in
itself create the follow stuff meet we
need to move much faster we cannot sit
in circle in groups from Babel with
strangers all day long I think anything
magical is going to come out of that at
all
no we need a few people who go forward
work hard do their deep studies listen
to the elders and wisdom taking the full
perspective and then create the Falak
that means you got to get out of the
cave ironically Plato's cave the cave
that John is sucking he's decorated the
cave fantastically it's not that I
criticized the Container dr. Marquez
grating he's the best fucking container
constructor we've ever had
he's brilliant at it yes if I want to
belong somewhere and have a tip next to
me and feed on inside a room I'd go
straight into the tent John for variks
created for me but I will not find
purpose there and I'm a man so that
means to look outside the cave he was
saying that he thought that purpose was
not the only thing and he was kind of
arguing a bit against purpose he's
making a common mistake among scientists
okay I'm a psychoanalyst I do art he's a
psychologist he does sons
you're probably psychology psychologists
go and ask people questions or what they
find important in their lives they don't
first look at society and decide what
they could expect to have as an answer
my critique of young for warka when he
says that people not looking for purpose
is the total bullshit they're looking
for perfect more than ever but they
don't even have the self-confidence to
tell the psychologist that they do that
that's how nihilistic we are so they
will say they just want to belong
somewhere as if they wanted at it to
live next it no they want purpose that
means as a man I would start to look
outside the cave it's beautiful but it's
full of women and children singing
Kumbaya all day long and I hate that oh
you've been there too right that's why
you do Tantra right that is what they
create I just see they the risk here is
to repeating the mistake or creating
another typical California New Age
anomaly people are dressed in white
clothes to smile all the time and you go
crazy because there's no life to it it's
just women and children and tits inand
come by our little no you're gonna get
out of that there's something
fundamentally wrong with this place this
is not you right right you want to get
out of that and wait that's right
there's what I love about Peter tousle
term study you don't gave me the
vertical and horizontal it's brilliant
you got side the horizontal and
historically you know from the world of
the leg and so does John former key you
know the axis mundi so what is the first
thing you see when you get outside of
the cave you see a spy and you see
ground
mm-hmm and from the ground up to the sky
you see the actors Mundi a vertical
world and
vertical world consists of sex Menem art
and violence all the things you cannot
control but that can interrupt your life
at any given moment and cause havoc in
your life and with John Tavares well
they were there on to that like the idea
what's the rationale to or something
like that oh this is completely rational
it's not like it's not like it's not
like the bard
absolute storms into our lives and we in
make this is meaning no if you sit in a
car with your family and your car
crashes your entire family dies and
you're the only one who survives but
doesn't give you meaning it's horror but
it is life it is the divine this is
religion religion if it breaks into our
childish infantile fat lazy little
fantasies all right out there and kicks
us in the ass like a metric would and
tells us you gotta get out there and
find the damn chief can and find the
damn priests to leave you and your tribe
do something meaningful mm-hmm that is
religion and and this is what I mean
with phallus worship I am serious about
this I I think there's one guy who gets
it in America and gets it and he's a
tour de force but he's a German and
that's Peter theme he gets it and and I
want to wear tell me about guys I don't
know if I've I've looked at Peter enough
to be able to understand exactly where
he's coming from so maybe you can see
why he gets it and what is what that
means and sorry about the Swede sir but
sorry Nick Bostrom and Max tegmark are
not philosophers at all they just little
Egyptian boy pharaohs who write books
that are just about you know what boys
dream about God there was too much Star
Trek I'm Freddy North head oh no Peter
field is a philosopher he is a real
philosophical mind he's brilliant and I
wonder where did he arrive at exactly
the same conclusions that John said
exist and our team is talking why did I
write exactly same conclusion which
conclusions what
how do you dig that deep into Hegel Marx
Freud meetcha to get a four
understanding where at and I discovered
he did that to cos meet Leo Strauss okay
now that's the ultimate Cain and Abel
relationship you want what you have you
read called Schmidt or have you read Lee
no nose no okay this is this is a coach
MIT was the German Nazi super
philosopher right yeah I've heard of
them yeah yeah so if you read political
philosophy or III theology yeah you'll
have to read Col Smith because his
genius was the discovery at the
separation of church and state another
mistake from Christianity again to keep
children away from garden so what cost
et cetera said that this is ridiculous
politics and theology are one of the
same thing so he created an idea of
political theology and that's exactly
what he created up he created a
political ideology to celebrated pathos
celebrated six and the art and violence
to the extent and he completely forgot
about logos and that is fascism so so
cosmic and you did that that's exactly
if you're leftist think or a rightist
think or whatever you do politics you
cannot avoid cosmic you can't even do
political ideology without studying
coach Smith first the consummate in
parallel with him had a Jewish friend
called Leo Strauss and they'd be sorely
kept in contact throughout all these
years no Strauss obviously left Germany
like so many brilliant minds did went to
America and he's one of the 20th
century's most precious thinkers he's a
brilliant thinker so Peter Thiel has
arrived and understanding that the lack
of phallus is at the center of the
meeting crisis in his right there by
going there through Kozma the Leo
Strauss and the understanding between
trade routes he's written a brilliant
paper called the straw Sein moment that
is on a part definitely with the work we
do that is how fucking brilliant Peter
Thiel is and I am getting connected I
guess with the people around him in
America and I think we need to start
collaborating on that level now because
the problem we got is that if they're
too much of this worship of the magical
emergence coming
from out of nowhere suddenly a
self-organization solves our problems if
people seriously believe that if that
sort of effeminate magical religion that
hates and scared to death of the fallacy
if that takes root it becomes the
dominant mode we know historically
remote parlays with my hair yeah I mean
we know that historically if that
happens we're in a really really bad
place because that's exactly what
happened in Egypt before at Naughton
that's extracted what happened in
Germany before Hitler that's exactly the
mess rush I would say before Stalin came
along this was the Miss China was in
after Japan had raped it to bits in the
1940s and Maul came along and ten years
later mouth started the Cultural
Revolution you know about to talk about
the Silk Road mm-hmm constantly that
Silk Road is the most magnificent
project humanity rebelled
there is also an inverted dark secret
and the dark soldier was created in the
20th century and as a cell code that
goes from Hitler to stall him to Mao the
pole vault mm-hm and it has a name on it
and that name is Brussels mm-hmm if we
keep worshiping little children as if
they were gods
we are resourceful mm-hmm and that can
only open up the space for a little
child God to step forward and say you're
gonna follow me and then all of the side
will be in a state of Lord of the Flies
hmm
y'over market is serious about wisdom
and so on I but I think he I think he
needs to understand that maybe does but
needs to understand that infant wisdom
is a big myth and he needs to deal with
agnosticism and deal with the plate
unless I'm involved in this that's where
I'm eating I am I am totally anti plate
honest I'm definitely at our start
Liga's Plato and I think Iraq leaders
was the most brilliant of the Greeks and
I think Zoroaster is the real root of
philosophy not the brakes and we need to
go back to prior to the axle age to
these guys who came out of the nomadic
life and put down the normandy ology
into texts and try to create the legend
that fitted human beings
and the message today in the 21st
century is that we need to get Humanity
on the move again in ideas and
physically we need to get them out of
the illusion that the permanent
settlement was ever a safe harbor for
Humanity it isn't we need to get on the
move again and I think the return of the
global.nomads
we went to that term 25 years ago that's
the new elite I think the people who are
the anywhere should be the winners I
think the summers will be bitter losers
and I think the new elite that would
step forward the network rats we talk
about or nematic again it's a we know
meditation humanik that's the key that
is a return to the Naaman ology we've
turned to the origin the practice for
50,000 a belieber doors and and hmm no
no no no no no don't drive no we haven't
so many problems we haven't sought we
this is not a Christian fantasy at all
this is not a plate on its perfection
and no more didn't mean oh no no no it's
just that it is at your main way of
dealing with you Minh beings this is
what human beings can handle with our
minds and operate with it so I
understand what he does every day I mean
I understand I understand that I
understand that we need borders that
work we need member in theory we need
intelligent Porter's or the soup
reporters like that but I think I think
the global Empire has happened I think
it's technological I think the machines
had already decided but they already
have a global Empire I think the
machines are developed right now they
will instantly in a second as soon as
they start to pick up on things
understand they are free to roam the
earth as they wish and I think it's
human beings are stuck in small mindsets
we're stuck in tribes in clans at best
nations
were terrified of the Empire and we need
to go back to so roster who is the only
guy ever
who said I wish to create a religion for
all humanity
and understood what that meant so for me
the picture is that door a schism in
Judaism or grown-up religions in
Christianity and Islam or the
bastardization of those two religions
and we need to deal with that and I
think Cartesian individualism that got
stuck in Europe became the America state
religion after the 17th century
it's a bastardization again of
Christianity we haven't developed at all
as human beings we've lost track and we
lost track over the last four thousand
years and this is the price we're paying
for the illusion that we could settle
permanently somewhere and magic will
just come from the sky and we will never
have to make an effort ever again you
know it's just it's some you know yeah
okay I'm not alone in this I know other
people who are or getting there too I
think I think the deeps don't I guess
kind of stasis of just sort of you know
you know this extreme stasis or
something no I don't think this is
stasis at all did it's a beautiful word
an ancient person that cannot be
translated and it's called fresh
creating and the fresh canopy is the
state of ever renewal yeah but I'm
saying you're criticizing the state of
stasis and oh yeah yeah the posing a
state of renewal yes yes yes yes you're
saying that we need to move get on the
move you could just look you can just
look at the beautiful plate of scale
that doesn't provide is talking about he
probably agrees with me and maybe I have
over criticized or have been over
critical here maybe then to make a point
then I'm only happier I and I want to
hear what he has to say and I want to be
smarter and I won't have a better view
and I think certainly details in the
world that you're working on on this
idea of the numerology we all obviously
fulfilling what Jill Diller set out to
do you know the greatest thinker of the
20th century he created the term no
mythology he talked about the military
talked about the shaman's who could be
no much but we're talking about the
entire humanity has to become nomadic
again to survive and we know it for a
fact we go to the gym you know we all
know that if he just lined bad we died
from obesity
No and and we're also discovering that
yeah we look beautiful with sexually
attractive woman 20 but we know shit no
get the sex dolls in there and remind us
that well that's was easy it was easy to
look great but it's damn hard work to be
a fascinating and creative person who
has wisdom and that is most value again
you must uh must be the husband there we
agree completely all of us anything we
agree on
it's possible that I focus too much on
the phallic because I don't see any more
well yeah that one question out yeah
that's that I actually that was one of
my questions you you anticipated one of
my questions that people might interpret
you as being sort of fellow centric or
male centric or or you know no open your
philosophy is that I know you're not I'm
saying now being found eccentric means
that if the man get the shit together
the women reap the benefits they get
more shoes yeah they could do their shit
anyway giving birth to children they do
wonderfully so and they do so many other
things I mean for God's look at the tons
of junk or cement or two right now and I
love the two bits and we need female
leaders because the men are not up to it
yeah men have screwed up so we certainly
during a long period now neither on
strong women take physicals but the the
magical perspective and when I heard of
one of these lovely friendly
conversations with John and we so far we
talked through you in public and then we
talking private directly and I just told
him straight off I said why don't you
just come out as the screaming Buddhists
you are because to me John is the
perfect Buddhist to match my
Zoroastrianism he doesn't want to be a
Buddhist he doesn't wanna he is a
Buddhist
what else is he he knows the Japanese he
knows the guys he knows Tibet he knows
the Buddha he he's he's a formidable
Buddhist scholar and and in the sort of
Plato's came the horizontal religion
he's talking to the religion of the
horizontal world that he's talking about
he doesn't beautiful God's sake I broke
the citizen book to celebrate guys like
him I don't have a problem with that I'm
just wanted to complement the picture
say there's something lacking that could
even be dangerous if we don't see it and
it's like philosophically speaking it's
like it's very common but John has made
the jump from Iman account straight to
Heidegger and then because Hydra girls
are not see he takes on the Christian
Heidegger is Paul Tillich and all those
50 lecturers who gave arrived with
putting Paul Tillich there as his barred
absolute so ok I don't do that
I think count was the last of the boy
Pharaohs and it's Hegel who takes double
count and my god when you start to
understand how Hegel thinks you
understand what thinking is and it's
fantastic and you get way more
intelligence because of it and you start
to think negations know that and and you
get the picture and you also get how
misunderstood Hegel is but he's
brilliant and his sons are Nietzsche
Freud Marx
you know you'll eventually they're also
incidentally
if we hadn't started thinking negation
we couldn't even have discovered our own
son consciousness no we couldn't have
the realizations we have today it would
have been impossible hmm that's for a
man so I think I don't think you can
jump to Heidegger because it becomes a
very individual existential project of
some kind of self-indulgent self
transformation that's where extension
arise I force people to go back out of
the world I remind you that the
Celestials don't like the monks and the
nuns of the world they don't like the
people who sit there out in the forest
no Hermits and all that they say no
you're part of society and you do walk
out into the forest to retract you only
do it to see the world better hmm so you
can come back and have a bigger view you
become a satellite you see the big of
you then you come back into the village
and you ran out with a village and you
engage your archetype and you do what
you should do as a man or a woman to
contribute to this product
this is or asterism mmm-hmm this is
called Asha Taoism does the same thing
it's called Tao Zen too maybe the you
know you've got you come back to the
marketplace with there
all the same Zen in Japan is shot in
China is en in Vietnam is selm
in Korea is Dana interest in Iran and no
if Diana in northern India and is Dianna
Gianna Gianna Indian Soros and Iran is
the same thing it's yoga meditation
spiritual practice martial arts here's
what we completely agree completely
don't forget we need the resurrection of
all these traditions we've got a team
here in Sweden out in the spring even
working on resurrecting this Alaska
martial arts so as to know because the
rescue meditation is beautiful and I
love synthesis amanda says that I love
this awakening a religious practices
I completely agree with John for Varkey
that religion comes from underneath and
it's practices but then you cannot
escape politics you cannot say that you
you cannot create a ligand we pretend
sex does not exist you cannot create or
anywhere you pretend violence does not
exist you cannot create the religion
where you don't really pretend art does
not exist which leads your bevel and so
those things must exist and they must be
included and a real religion if it's
going to make clean break Christianity
and create proper religion it really it
would definitely include and we try to
domesticate but also celebrate the
forces of sex and art and violence
that's when the file is including
religion which means the church and
state cannot be separate a proper legend
understands that all of society's
religious in church and state going
separate ways exactly what creates a
state that is irresponsible and
employers the planet which exactly what
the European states did it is the way to
contain the forces of nature to contain
the forces in nature inside ourselves
hmm
that's Hegel's that's Freud's that's
Jung's point mm-hmm I have this
the two rivers coming to my head again
yeah that is a very strong image never
not got a credit this I got a credit
Peter Towson in my team for that he's
yeah he's he's good he's good he's
really good with us proud to work in the
team collaborated wonderful guy it's
it's so striking you know it's like you
read Marshall McLuhan right mm-hmm and
you realize that the way we communicate
determines how we think sure Aristotle
we talked about it iris Tottenham iris
Italian Revival now for a long time it's
really happening
if you're radical enough you take
Aristotle's critique of Plato what is
tells Plato you don't understand context
and if you don't stand the context
within which things happen you
understand anything
yeah okay so there is the tale your
revival is all about rediscovering
context the radical way of doing that
now we have access to the last ten
thousand years of history where access
actually did genetically to human beings
for the last two hundred thousand years
we can finally scientifically so date of
the apology understand your means that
is fantastic if your letters to tell you
because then you can study how the
landscape we live in shape our thinking
and can you see now why exactly it not
don't happen in Egypt and why Sir aster
happen in Mesopotamia mmm-hmm so that
loes shift made all the difference
between the one River civilization and
the two river civilization and theology
has argued ever since about the
Trinity's you know about the dualities
what is the father what is the Sun what
is the rain go what is the Sun God what
is the split within the fellows I want
to go deeply into this and I intend to
call it phallus theory and follow
studies and I don't mean that as a
medical doctor I mean that as a
philosopher what are what are the
different aspects of follows I mean
there's the root of the phallus that's a
history that's deep history would come
from and there's the phallus in the
sense that the phallus is the dream
where we're going I think we need a
great grand new narrative at least for a
small elite that can then set an example
that others can follow that's a neat
perspective or hopefully if it's
possible some kind of collaboration
between man and machine
yeah that creates a sustainable world
that actually is interesting we live it
interesting the name for that is a
fashion cadet they in in August an
ancient Iranian we're gonna live in a
world of permanent change from now on
there are no options that's what's gonna
happen now if that's what's happening
now they know them at all our gops the
term we use the borrowed absolutes is
what we're up against and this is
probably than the book about the last of
all Exodus with the last exit isn't
whatever we don't know that it's
certainly an exodus book but to all your
listeners out there you want to
contribute and collaborate with us we
don't know where the exodus is going we
don't have the name for the state the
permanent change well we have you know
obviously how this or a student's names
for it that's what we use those word
Farish karana the--and the ha'la'tha
but we don't have a you know a gutsy
ballsy name that works in the english
language or in European languages sense
where we're going new Babylon is the
wrong metaphor Jerusalem is over and
babylons over and urbanization is over
well geography is over space is dying
even in physics but you know very
concentrated world you know it's just
fascinating but we don't have a name for
that yet well we we have all those
terminology the phallic gaze barred
absolute no mythology the terms are
there the velocity of the Hegelian all
that psychoanalytical certainly but yeah
some of these bread kids out there go
all the way through and listen through
all these sessions we do you and i find
the depth in them that's bear um yeah i
think i think the audience is slowly
growing it's it's bigger on there now in
the podcast that it is on the youtube i
noticed just fuckin good good good so
they can stop looking at my red nose and
actually hear what I'm saying well it's
a bus almost equally you're handsome you
know they would think if they
favor you they would look at YouTube and
can it ever win the election if they
favorite made they would listen to the
radio and Nixon with the election no not
true yes you have a beer you have a
great beard hot usually your pajamas and
really you can tell you live in France
you're handsome you're not going to be
traveling a lot this year doing stuff
together
yeah we'll plan to go to Canada together
we love Toronto we love all the ships
that's going on there and see what we
can make out of that